{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"pulmonary edema and circulatory failure.",
					"enlarged lymph nodes and extreme pain.",
					"necrosis of muscle tissue and cell destruction.",
					"intestinal obstruction and severe sepsis."
				],
				"question": "When introduced into the body, ricin causes:",
				"source": "See Biologic Agents"
			},
			"back": "pulmonary edema and circulatory failure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"potentiation.",
					"weaponization.",
					"alkalization.",
					"dissemination."
				],
				"question": "The process performed to artificially maximize the target population’s exposure to a biologic agent, thereby exposing the greatest number of people and achieving the desired result, is called:",
				"source": "See Weapons of Mass Destruction"
			},
			"back": "weaponization."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Hydrogen cyanide",
					"Phosgene oxime",
					"Carbon monoxide",
					"Organophosphates"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following agents blocks the body’s ability to use oxygen and possesses an odor similar to almonds?",
				"source": "See Chemical Agents"
			},
			"back": "Hydrogen cyanide"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Cutaneous anthrax has a 90% mortality rate.",
					"Anthrax is a deadly virus that replicates.",
					"Pulmonary anthrax is the deadliest form.",
					"There is presently no vaccine against anthrax."
				],
				"question": "Which of the following statements regarding anthrax is correct?",
				"source": "See Biologic Agents"
			},
			"back": "Pulmonary anthrax is the deadliest form."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"unplanned.",
					"nuclear attacks.",
					"impulsive.",
					"covert."
				],
				"question": "Most terrorist attacks are:",
				"source": "See EMT Response to Terrorism"
			},
			"back": "covert."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"neutron.",
					"beta.",
					"gamma.",
					"alpha."
				],
				"question": "The least harmful form of ionizing radiation is:",
				"source": "See Radiologic/Nuclear Devices"
			},
			"back": "alpha."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"violent religious group.",
					"single-issue terrorist group.",
					"extremist political group.",
					"group of domestic terrorists."
				],
				"question": "The chemical attacks that occurred in Tokyo between 1994 and 1995 were carried out by a(n):",
				"source": "See What Is Terrorism?"
			},
			"back": "violent religious group."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"nervous system.",
					"skin.",
					"vascular system.",
					"respiratory tract."
				],
				"question": "The primary route of exposure of vesicant agents is the:",
				"source": "See Chemical Agents"
			},
			"back": "skin."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"are of different shapes and sizes.",
					"are identical in their development.",
					"initially form on the lower trunk.",
					"develop early during the disease."
				],
				"question": "The skin lesions associated with smallpox:",
				"source": "See Biologic Agents"
			},
			"back": "are identical in their development."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"type of material used to manufacture the device.",
					"pressure that is generated from the explosion itself.",
					"patient’s distance from the epicenter of the explosion.",
					"size of the structure that was involved in the explosion."
				],
				"question": "The type and severity of wounds sustained from incendiary and explosive devices primarily depend on the:",
				"source": "See Incendiary and Explosive Devices"
			},
			"back": "patient’s distance from the epicenter of the explosion."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"an ecoterrorist attack.",
					"apocalyptic violence.",
					"state-sponsored terrorism.",
					"domestic terrorism."
				],
				"question": "The 1996 Summer Olympics bombing is an example of:",
				"source": "See Active Shooter Events"
			},
			"back": "domestic terrorism."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"locate the medical staging officer to obtain his or her assignment.",
					"begin triaging patients and start treating the most critical ones.",
					"contact the EMS medical director and obtain further instructions.",
					"remain in the rehabilitation area until he or she is assigned a task."
				],
				"question": "If the incident command system is already established at the scene of a terrorist attack, the EMT should:",
				"source": "See EMT Response to Terrorism"
			},
			"back": "locate the medical staging officer to obtain his or her assignment."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Phosgene",
					"Soman",
					"Chlorine",
					"Lewisite"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following chemicals is a nerve agent?",
				"source": "See Chemical Agents"
			},
			"back": "Soman"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"have a slow onset of symptoms.",
					"cause high fever.",
					"cause skin blistering.",
					"are not contagious."
				],
				"question": "Unlike viruses and bacteria, neurotoxins:",
				"source": "See Biologic Agents"
			},
			"back": "are not contagious."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"attack the bone marrow and destroy cells.",
					"seep out of the blood vessels and tissues.",
					"engorge the brain and cause hemorrhaging.",
					"become thick and spontaneously clot."
				],
				"question": "Viral hemorrhagic fevers (VHF), such as Ebola, cause the blood to:",
				"source": "See Biologic Agents"
			},
			"back": "seep out of the blood vessels and tissues."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"an EMT is exposed to a victim who has not yet been decontaminated.",
					"an EMT has direct contact with a chemical agent at a terrorist incident.",
					"two EMTs are exposed to the same agent after being decontaminated.",
					"an EMT provides care to a victim after the victim has been decontaminated."
				],
				"question": "Cross-contamination occurs when:",
				"source": "See EMT Response to Terrorism"
			},
			"back": "an EMT is exposed to a victim who has not yet been decontaminated."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"The dirty bomb, because of its ability to cause massive damage over a large geographic area, is an effective WMD.",
					"Dirty bombs could injure victims with both radioactive material and the explosive material used to deliver it.",
					"Dirty bombs contain significant amounts of radioactive material and are capable of being delivered via a missile.",
					"The effectiveness of a dirty bomb is solely dependent on the amount of alpha radiation that it emits."
				],
				"question": "Which of the following statements regarding a “dirty bomb” is correct?",
				"source": "See Radiologic/Nuclear Devices"
			},
			"back": "Dirty bombs could injure victims with both radioactive material and the explosive material used to deliver it."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"the spectrum of signs that define a disease.",
					"any agent that acts as a carrier or transporter.",
					"the ability of a virus or bacterium to be spread.",
					"the period of time between exposure and illness."
				],
				"question": "A disease vector is defined as:",
				"source": "See Biologic Agents"
			},
			"back": "any agent that acts as a carrier or transporter."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"single-issue group.",
					"violent religious group.",
					"extremist political group.",
					"doomsday cult."
				],
				"question": "An attack on an abortion clinic would most likely be carried out by a(n):",
				"source": "See What Is Terrorism?"
			},
			"back": "single-issue group."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-41-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"weapons of mass destruction are distributed.",
					"antidotes, antibiotics, and vaccines are distributed.",
					"chemical weapons are manufactured and distributed.",
					"chemical and biologic weapons are stockpiled."
				],
				"question": "Points of distribution (PODs) are strategically placed facilities where:",
				"source": "See Biologic Agents"
			},
			"back": "antidotes, antibiotics, and vaccines are distributed."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-41",
		"label": "Chapter 41"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}